[
    {
        "question": "In Portugal, what object is traditionally thrown at friends in celebration of April Fool`s Day?",
        "answer": "Flour (Flour bombing` is an established April Fool`s Day practice in Portugal and some other countries.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which continent would you find Andorra?",
        "answer": "Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Andorra is bordered by which two countries?",
        "answer": "France and Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of New Hampshire?",
        "answer": "Concord"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concord is the capital of which US State?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state New Hampshire?",
        "answer": "Concord"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?",
        "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pashto is the official language of which country?",
        "answer": "Afghanistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What tree appears on the national flag of Lebanon?",
        "answer": "Cedar tree"
    },
    {
        "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Mumbai in India was formerly known by what name?",
        "answer": "Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Because it entered the union in 1876, what western US state is nicknamed `The Centennial State`?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two Great Lakes are connected by the Straits of Mackinac?",
        "answer": "Michigan and Huron"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you celebrate `Carnival`?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Japanese word for `dog`?",
        "answer": "Inu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Al-Azhar, the oldest University in the Arab world, is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which former Soviet Republic was known as the `Bread Basket of the Empire`?",
        "answer": "Ukraine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Central American country`s highest elevation point is Cerro Chirripo at 3,810 meters?",
        "answer": "Costa Rica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Skopje is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Macedonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Skopje is the capital of which Eastern European country?",
        "answer": "Macedonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is directly northwest of Windsor, Ontario?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what river is the capital city of Canada located?",
        "answer": "Ottawa River"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river does the capital of Canada lie?",
        "answer": "Ottawa River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Romania?",
        "answer": "Bucharest"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?",
        "answer": "Kiev"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Sweden?",
        "answer": "Stockholm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Norway?",
        "answer": "Oslo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Finland?",
        "answer": "Helsinki"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the oldest airport in the world that`s still in operation?",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is known for the art of water puppetry?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city has the world`s largest network of aerial cable cars?",
        "answer": "La Paz, Bolivia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the world`s smallest penguin?",
        "answer": "Tasmania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s highest inhabited city?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. city has the most coffee shops per capita?",
        "answer": "Juneau, Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Steamboat Geyser?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Mountain State`?",
        "answer": "West Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What modern-day US state was inhabited by the Pequot Indians?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cape Fear River flows into what body of water?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What region was explored by Vitus Bering?",
        "answer": "Arctic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to the Pribilof Islands?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European city is nicknamed `Auld Reekie`?",
        "answer": "Edinburgh"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the capital of East Germany until 1990?",
        "answer": "East Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country has 61 as its International Calling Code?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the International Calling Code for Australia?",
        "answer": "61"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?",
        "answer": "Raleigh"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country will you find the cities Toledo and Granada?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the Peace Tower part of the Canadian Parliament Buildings?",
        "answer": "Ottawa, Ontario"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Ghana?",
        "answer": "Accra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is the capital of Tuscany?",
        "answer": "Florence"
    }
]